<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Forrest Ye's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://forresty.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://forresty.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-10T02:11:26+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://forresty.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Forrest Ye]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[strip trailing whitespaces automatically in TextMate2]]></title>
    <link href="http://forresty.com/blog/2012/01/09/strip-trailing-whitespaces-automatically-in-textmate2/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-09T12:45:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://forresty.com/blog/2012/01/09/strip-trailing-whitespaces-automatically-in-textmate2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been using TextMate2 the moment its alpha was out, and it has already proved itself good enough for my day-to-day coding tasks.</p>

<p>But there&#8217;s a problem: I want my codes to be absolutely clean, and trailing whitespaces in lines end really bug me.</p>

<p>Though there&#8217;s a command in Text Bundle which allows you to manually do the task, I would love TextMate to remove them automatically for me.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>By default it doesn&#8217;t have such functionality, but fortunately after some research through the Internet, I found a solution here:</p>

<p><a href="http://reinteractive.net/posts/4-stripping-whitespace-out-of-textmate-2">http://reinteractive.net/posts/4-stripping-whitespace-out-of-textmate-2</a></p>

<p>In a nutshell, you need to create a custom bundle with a custom command looks like this:</p>

<p><img src="http://forresty.com/images/textmate2-strip-whitespaces.png"></p>

<p>It utilizes following script, which is shamelessly copied from Text Bundle in TextMate:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/1581221.js?file='></script>
<noscript><pre><code>#!/usr/bin/env bash
[[ -f &quot;${TM_SUPPORT_PATH}/lib/bash_init.sh&quot; ]] &amp;&amp; . &quot;${TM_SUPPORT_PATH}/lib/bash_init.sh&quot;

perl -pe 's/[\t ]+$//g'
</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>And that&#8217;s it. Each time you pressed CMD + S, all trailing whitespaces in lines end are automatically removed before the document is saved. Cheers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[back to work]]></title>
    <link href="http://forresty.com/blog/2012/01/09/back-to-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-09T10:52:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://forresty.com/blog/2012/01/09/back-to-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been months since I put down this site, and it&#8217;s been months since I left moregg to explore a path of my own.</p>

<p>It was a great time.</p>

<p>I made a serious mistake by trying to walk the &#8220;PM&#8221; path before becoming a good engineer, and now finally I am able to make things right.
Finally I was able slow down and learn technical stuffs real seriously, covering the fine details behind each and every problem I encountered.</p>

<p>Just sit down, take a deep breath, and started to train myself into a hacker. It takes time, but I have plenty of time.</p>

<p>I learnt Ruby the hard way. I learnt Rails the hard way. I started to re-learn Objective-C and the art of iOS app development.
I started to solve problems on projecteuler.net and share codes on Github.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I signed up online courses from Stanford: mlclass, aiclass and dbclass, and finished them all with good grades,
simply because I regret did not learn them well at college.</p>

<p>I started to read in English most of the time, and I read a lot.
After realizing the painful truth that most things written in Chinese (to be precise, Simplified Chinese) are garbages,
I know I have to master English, perhaps some more other languages as well.
Thank you my Kindle for being my beloved and trusted friend.</p>

<p>And now I am writing too.</p>

<p>Then I started to develop a taste in music. I was never really into music before, but thanks to Spotify and iTunes Store and a peaceful mind,
I got to know a lot of bands and understand different genres.
Now I cannot imagine my life without music, sometimes they are so good that they almost made me cry.</p>

<p>I even started to learn playing guitar.</p>

<p>I learnt to cook. Eating healthy and delicious foods in China could be either challenging or luxury. And I have to take care of myself.</p>

<p>I started to travel. More and more. And I am pretty sure there will be even more. While I would appreciate some great traveling companions,
traveling alone is quite a rewarding experience.</p>

<p>Mind control, brain wash, poor education, incredible high living pressures,
blind Patriotism and lack of faith are destroying the younger generation of this country,
and thus bring about uncertainty to the future, or even pose danger on the entire human race.
To fight back, I started to provide anti-Great-Firewall-of-China solutions and technical supports for my friends,
something I thought I would never do because it would be categorized into &#8220;fixing the computer&#8221;.</p>

<p>And after I reclaimed my free will and completed my self-guided rebirth, I suddenly realized I started to know how to love.</p>

<p>It is just, different.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s the kind of human affection which drives you crazy, to do things you have never done before, and have the courage to face any difficulties.</p>

<p>And I learnt how to hate.</p>

<p>I started to believe that integrity, kindness, generosity, freewill, bravery, audacity and all other sorts of human virtues are
the foundamentals of modern human society. Without the right values, a person with greater power can do more harm than good.</p>

<p>And that&#8217;s why I don&#8217;t like most so-called successful people in China.</p>

<p>And that&#8217;s why I hate China. And that&#8217;s why I am leaving.</p>

<p>Everything that has a beginning has an end.
Now, as time calls, hereby I formally announce that I am back to work, ending my gap year early since I have more important things to do.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s been a great journey, but It&#8217;s time to start a new adventure. It will be fun.</p>

<p>I think I am more than ready.</p>

<p>If my life is meant to be running at the speed of 180 MPH, so be it :)</p>

<p>Hell, I am back to work.</p>

<p>To infinity and beyond.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
