<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Forrest Ye's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://forresty.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://forresty.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-09T11:33:58+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://forresty.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Forrest Ye]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[back to work]]></title>
    <link href="http://forresty.com/blog/2012/01/09/back-to-work/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-09T10:52:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://forresty.com/blog/2012/01/09/back-to-work</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been months since I put down the original forresty.com, and it&#8217;s been months since I left moregg to explore a path of my own.</p>

<p>It was a great time. Finally I was able to learn technical stuffs real seriously, covering the fine details behind each problem I encountered.</p>

<p>Just calm down, deep breath, and started to train myself into a hacker. It takes time, and I have plenty of time.</p>

<p>I learnt Ruby the hard way. I learnt Rails the hard way. I started to re-learn Objective-C and the art of iOS app development.</p>

<p>I signed up online courses from Stanford: mlclass, aiclass and dbclass, and finished them all.</p>

<p>I started to read in English most of the time, and I read a lot. And now I am writing too. Kindle is my beloved and trusted friend.</p>

<p>I started to develop a taste in music. I started to learn playing guitar.</p>

<p>I learnt to cook.</p>

<p>I started to travel. More and more.</p>

<p>I started to learn how to love. Truly madly deeply.</p>

<p>But now, well, hereby I formally announce that I am back to work, ending my gap year early since I have more important things to do.</p>

<p>I think I am more than ready.</p>

<p>If my life is meant to be running at the speed of 180 MPH, so be it :)</p>

<p>Hell, I am back to work.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
